Allan Marquand Papers, 1858-1951 (bulk 1878-1950): Finding Aid C0269
Manuscripts Division
- Series 4: Photographs, undated; 3 boxes
  - Subseries 4C: Photograph Album, undated; 1 box
    - Album, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 51)
      photographs of Princeton buildings, grounds, and classmates
- Series 5: Memorabilia, undated; 1 box
  This series consists of several folders of memorabilia, especially from Marquand's school days at St. Paul's School in New Hampshire.
  - Memorabilia, undated; 3 folders (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
- Series 6: Miscellaneous Material, 1887-1924; 5 boxes
  This series consists of subject files of miscellaneous material relating to Marquand's interests.
  Organized into broad subject areas: Princeton-related, Battle Monument of Princeton, and another grouping of smaller files of alphabetically-arranged subjects.
  - Subseries 6A: Princeton, including the Department of Art and Archaeology, dates not examined; 1 box
    Consists of material related to The Daily Princetonian, Department of Art and Archaeology (including examinations), Graduate School, reports, and committees, as well as others.
    Arranged by subject of material.
    - The Daily Princetonian, Princeton Alumni Weekly, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Department of Art and Archaeology, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Department of Art and Archaeology Examinations, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Evelyn College, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Graduate School, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Miscellany, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Official Register; Annual Report of the President, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Preceptorial Method, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Reports, Committees, etc., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - School of Architecture, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 6B: Battle Monument of Princeton, 1887-1922; 2 boxes
    Consists of documents, correspondence, meeting minutes, clippings, and sketches related to the Battle Monument of Princeton.
    - "The Battle of Princeton" by Samuel Craig Cowart; "The Starry Banner of the Free"; "The Spirit of '76", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 1)
      written by Cowart on the occasion of the dedication of the Princeton Battle Monument
    - Battle Monument, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Site I galley sheets
    - Brandywine Battlefield, 1922; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 3)
      identification of markers
    - Documents, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - National Sculpture Society Form of competition for sculpture signed: F. S. C., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Inscription on Battle Monument, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Dean A. West
    - Letterhead Envelopes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - List of Subscribers to Princeton Battle Monument, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Minutes of the Princeton Monument Committee, 1887 January 1-1922 April 30; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 9)
      C. S. Robinson, Allan Marquand, William Libbey
    - "National Monuments" by Henry Van Dyke, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - News Releases and Clippings, 1922; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Pencil Sketch of Proposed Park, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 12)
      scale 1" = 50 feet
    - "A Proposed Small Park for Princeton", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Architect's Plan of the Battle Monument, dates not examined; 1 box (57 x 32" oversize folder) (Box 54)
  - Subseries 6C: Other Subjects, 1914; 2 boxes
    Consists of materials related to the Archaeological Institute of America, and Art, Archaeology, and Architecture, as well as others.
    - Archaeological Institute of America, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Art, Archaeology, and Architecture, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Bulletins and Catalogues, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - "Enoch's Pillars", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Logic Machine, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 5)
      The machine is on permanent display in the reference area of Fine Hall Library.
    - Marquand, Allan, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 6)
      memorial tributes
    - Marquand, Allan, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 7)
      newspaper clippings re: death in 1924
    - Petition, 1914; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 8)
      Société Nationale des Antiquaires de France re: the bombardment of Rheims Cathedral
    - Schools; Miscellaneous Subjects, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Glass Negatives (fragile), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 50)
- Series 7: Printed Matter, 1884-1908; 4 boxes
  This series consists primarily of copies of Marquand's publications in journals, articles about him, and art-related newspaper clippings.
  This series is arranged into two subseries: Allan Marquand as Author or Subject, and Miscellaneous Books, Clippings, etc.
  - Subseries 7A: Allan Marquand as Author or Subject, undated; 3 boxes
    Consists of printed material with Allan Marquand as author or subject, such as The Iconographic Encyclopedia, Vol. 3, Art in America, and Princeton College Bulletin, as well as others.
    - The Iconographic Encyclopedia, Vol. 3, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Art in America, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Scribner's Magazine, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Princeton College Bulletin, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - American Journal of Archaeology, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material about Allan Marquand, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 7B: Miscellaneous Books, Clippings, etc., 1884-1908; 1 box
    Consists of miscellanoeus books and clippings, including Adriaen Brouwer et Son Evolution Artistique and Les Della Robbia--Leur Vie et Leur Oeuvre.
    - Adriaen Brouwer et Son Evolution Artistique, 1908; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Les Della Robbia--Leur Vie et Leur Oeuvre, 1884; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbooks of Clippings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Series 8: Papers of Others, 1875-1950; 17 boxes
  This series consists of papers of persons other than Allan Marquand, particularly those of his wife, Eleanor, and his father, Henry, including writings, correspondence, and related printed matter.
  Organized in three subseries: one each for Marquand's wife and father, a third for everyone else, arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries 8A: Eleanor Cross Marquand, 1887-1952; 15 boxes
    These papers richly document Eleanor Marquand's professional interest in gardens and flowers and her involvement in associated organizations.
    Organized first by form/genre, the material is arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
    - Writings, 1923 May-1947 September; 7 boxes
      - "The Blaksley Botanic Garden", 1936 January; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 1)
        including correspondence, notes, and printed matter
      - "Concerning Tulips", 1940; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 2)
        written for the Princeton Garden Club's weekly contributions in the local paper
      - Dedication of Nurses Home, Trenton State Hospital, 1929 June; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 3)
        address, printed matter
      - "Essex County Gardens", 1934 March; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 4)
        from Bulletin of the Garden Club of America, including printed material
      - "The Family Tree in the Vegetable Garden", 1939 November; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 5)
        from Bulletin of the Garden Club of America
      - Ferns and Dern Allies of Louisiana, C. A. Brown & D. S. Correll Book Review, 1943 November; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 6)
        from The Monthly Bulletin of the Horticultural Society of New York
      - "Flora of Jekyl Island", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 7)
        including notes on Baca Grandee and correspondence
      - "The Flora of Jekyl Island", 1923 May; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 8)
        paper read before the Garden Club of Princeton
      - "Flowers of Ten Centuries", 1947 May; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 9)
        Morgan Library Exhibition, including notes, printed matter, & correspondence
      - Gerard's Herball: The essence thereof distilled by Marcus Woodward from the edition of Th. Hohnson, 1636 Book Review, 1928 December; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - "Ghosts of Gardens", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - "Grapes", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - "The History of Plant Illustration to 1850", 1941 February 20-March 31; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 13)
        joint exhibition of the Grolier Club and the American Garden Club
      - "Honolulu in 1937", 1947 September; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Horace Walpole: Gardenist by Isabel W. U. Chase Book review, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - "An Imaginary Garden", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Introduction for John Gill, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 4)
        The New York Botannical Gardens, Free Illustratred Lectures
      - Introduction of Dr. Allen O. Whipple at the Annual Meeting of the Ladies' Auxiliary, 1936 June; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Introduction of Mrs. Cheston, 1936 February 11; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 6)
        at the Garden Club of America
      - "Landscaping", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 7)
        from A Guide to the Princeton Campus and Its Treasures, including printed matter
      - "A Lover of Plants in California", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Manual of the Southeastern Flora by John Kunkel Small Book Review, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - "Martha's Vineyard", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - "Mrs. Henry has asked me to speak on a vision for the future, ...", 1938 May 9; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 11)
        talk
      - "Mrs. Hibben", 1932 May 6; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 12)
        from Princeton Alumni Weekly, including correspondence & printed matter
      - "Notes on John Bartram", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 13)
        manuscript and printed matter, Garden Club of America talk (?)
      - "Old-World Plants in a New-World Valley", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - "The Oldest of the University Herbals", 1939; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 15)
        correspondence and notes
      - On Modern Gardening-- An Essay by Horace Walpole, W.S. Lewis Book review, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - Our Wild Orchids, Trails and Portraits by Frank Morris & Edward H. Eames Book Review, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - Pagan Herb-Gatherers, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 18)
        manuscripts and notes
      - Pine Barrens Articles, dates not examined; 1 box
        - "Island Beach", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 19)
        - "The New Jersey Pine Barrens", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 19)
        - "Plants from New Jersey's Barrens", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 19)
        - "New Jersey Pine Barrens", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 19)
        - "Pine Barrens Flowers", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 19)
        - "Autumn in the New Jersey Pine Barrens", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - Pine Barrens Correspondence, 1938-1940; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 20)
      - Pine Barrens Miscellaneous Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 21)
      - "Plant Material in Santa Barbara Gardens", 1926 March; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 22)
        including correspondence and printed matter, Bulletin of the Garden Club of America
      - "The Plants and Plant Symbolism of the Unicorn Tapestries in the Cloisters Museum", 1937-1940; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 1)
        correspondence, printed matter, photographs of tapestries, notes
      - "Provence in June", 1927 March; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 2)
        from Bulletin of the Garden Club of America, photostats of flora
      - "Saffron", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 3)
        manuscripts, photostats, notes
      - "Some Ancient Gatherers of Herbs", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - "Some French Wild Flowers", 1928; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - "Some Horticultural Portraits" plus 1 letter, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 6)
        from Journal of the New York Botanical Garden
      - "Some Notes on the Decorative Arrangement of Cut flowers", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 7)
        paper read before the Princeton Garden Club (1919), the Bedford Garden Club (1920)
      - "Symbolic and Significant Plants in Art", 1946 March 12; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 8)
        talk at the Cosmopolitan Club, correspondence, notes, various versions in 1940, 1941, 1944, 1946
      - "Three Valleys in the Pyrenees", 1929 November; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - "To this audience, representing gardening interests from coast to coast...", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 10)
        talk (not delivered)
      - "The Trees of Guernsey", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 11)
        manuscript, correspondence, photographs, notes, printed matter
      - "The Trees of Guernsey", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 12)
        4" x 6" notecards
      - "Twenty-one years ago, we spent our first summer in Keene Valley...", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - "You ask for my recollections of that first meeting at Mrs. Henry's...", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 14)
        talk (?) re: The Princeton Garden Club
      - "When I first came to Princeton...", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - "When the world was very young, and before it had begun the drying-up process...", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - The World was My Garden by David Fairchild, Book review, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - Botanical Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Dioscorides, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 2)
        notes, correspondence
      - France, 1926; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Notes on Donald Egbert (including correspondence), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Notes on Herbs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Notes on Plants & Books, 1925; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Notes on Plants for Catalogues, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Notes on the Grand Canyon, 1924 February 6; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Notes on Trip to Hawaii, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Notes on Vegetables, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Notes on Yellowstone Park (Including Correspondence), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - "The Tikyll Psalter", 1933; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, dates not examined; 5 folders (Box 38, Folder 1-5)
      - Notes on 3" x 5" and 5" x 8" Cards, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 39)
      - Notebooks and Notes on Morgan Library's MS. 652 ("Dioscorides: Materia Medica"), 1941; 1 box (Box 52)
    - Correspondence, 1887-1952; 1 box
      - Alexander, Caroline, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Allen, Liley McM, 1898; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Armstrong, C, 1917; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Atkinson, Julia Yerkes, 1931-1941; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Aubert, Marcel, 1929; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Bancroft, George, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Barnhart, John Hendley, 1936; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - Breasted, James H., undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Brenner, Victor David, 1916; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - Burrage, Mildred, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 10)
      - Cameron, A. Guyot, 1917; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - Choate, Joseph H, 1907; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - Coomaraswamy, Ananda K, 1939; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 13)
      - Cotton, Adolph, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - Down, Joseph, 1939; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 15)
      - Downey, Glanville, 1939-1946; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 16)
      - Egbert, Donald D, 1940-1942; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 17)
      - Elderkin, George W. and Kate McK. Elderkin, 1941-1944; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 18)
      - Fetherolf, Frederick, Jr., undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 19)
      - Fitton, Elizabeth, 1939-1949; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 20)
      - Flanagan, John, 1917-1938; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 21)
      - Flexner, Abraham, 1940; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 22)
      - Forsyth, William, 1939; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 23)
      - French & Company Inc, 1937; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 24)
      - French, Daniel C, 1916; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 25)
      - Gardner, Isabella S., undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 26)
      - Garfield, H. A, 1908; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 27)
      - Gilman, Margaret, 1948; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 28)
      - Gish, Lillian, 1943; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 29)
      - Goldman, Hetty, 1944-1946; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 30)
      - Goldschmidt, Adolph, 1928-1940; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 31)
      - Goodrich, Sally, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 32)
      - Goodwin, A. A, 1903; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 33)
      - Hall, Elizabeth C, 1939; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 34)
      - Hanfmann, George M. A, 1937; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 35)
      - Harper, Francis, 1940; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 36)
      - Harrsen, Meta (Pierpont Morgan Library), 1949-1947; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 37)
      - Heyl, Lawrence, 1938-1939; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 38)
      - Hibben, John G, 1924; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 39)
      - Hitti, Philip K., undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 40)
      - Hofer, Philip, 1934; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 41)
      - The Horticultural Society of New York, Inc, 1940; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 42)
      - The John G. Johnson Art Collection, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 43)
        Henri Marceau (1939-1940), Barbara Sweeny, 7 TLsS
      - Kaneko, Viscount K., undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 44)
      - King, Louisa, 1933; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 45)
      - Krumbhaar, Edward B, 1942; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 46)
      - Learned, Emily C, 1947; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 47)
      - Leighton, John, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 48)
      - Lloyd, Richard W, 1939; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 49)
      - Maclegan, Eric, 1928; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 50)
      - MacMonnies, Frederick (1863-1937), 1907; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 51)
      - Marceau, Henri, 1943; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 52)
      - Marquand, Allan's death--Condolence notes to Mrs. Marquand and children, 1924; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 53)
        Including: Benjamin Ives Gilman, Arthur Twining Hadley, George W. Harper, Frederick MacMonnies, Charles Rufus Morey, Kennard Rand, Andrew F. West
      - Marquand, Eleanor Cross--Condolence notes to daughters, 1950; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 54)
        Sarnia Marquand, Eleanor Delanoy (Mrs. Douglas Delanoy), Mary Hochschild (Mrs. Harold Hochschild); correspondence, resolutions, printed matter
      - Maspero, Gaston, 1887; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 55)
      - McKnight, Martha H. B., undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 56)
      - Merrill, E. D, 1937; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 57)
      - Millet, G., undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 58)
      - Morey, Charles Rufus, 1940-1942; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 59)
      - New Jersey State Museum, 1942; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 60)
      - Osgood, Charles G, 1940; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 61)
      - Panofsky, Irwin, 1935-1952; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 62)
      - Perkins, Frances, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 63)
      - Pessel, Dr, 1935; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 64)
      - Preston, Frances Folsom Cleveland, 1929; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 65)
      - Princeton University Honorary Degree, 1948; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 66)
        Including: Harold Dodd, Glanville Downey, Abraham Flexner, Charles Rufus Morey, Erwin Panofsky, Bliss Perry, Datus Smith, Kurt Weitzmann
      - Rankin, Walter M, 1917; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 67)
      - Riley, Morgan T, 1941; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 68)
      - Sachs, Meta, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 69)
      - Salinger, Margaretta, M, 1943; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 70)
      - Savage, Henry L., undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 71)
      - Schad, Robert O, 1939; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 72)
      - Signatures, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 73)
        A. A. Berle, Jr., Aaron Copland, Philip Evergood
      - Sloane, Margaret D, 1935; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 74)
      - Svenson, Henry K, 1934; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 75)
      - Thomas, M. Carey, 1921; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 76)
      - Thompson, Charles D, 1904; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 77)
      - Van Dyke, Henry (1852-1933), 1927; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 78)
      - Voynich, E. L, 1931; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 79)
      - The Warburg Institute, 1938; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 80)
      - Weber, Shirley H, 1932; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 81)
      - Weinman, Adolph Alexander, 1916; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 82)
      - West, Andrew F, 1922; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 83)
      - White, Lynn Jr, 1947; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 84)
      - Wilber, Donald, 1940; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 85)
      - Williams, Jessie Lynch, 1920; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 86)
      - Wilson, Edith Bolling, 1944; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 87)
      - Wilson, Woodrow Thomas (1856-1924), 1912; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 88)
      - Unidentified Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 89)
    - Art and Botanical Photographs (including photostats and negatives), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 41)
    - Slides for Illustrated Lectures, undated; 1 box (Box 42)
    - Garden Club of America and Garden Club of Princeton, 1922-1947 July; 2 boxes
      - Badianus Manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Benjamin Franklin Exhibition, 1937 November 17-1938 January 7; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Book Exhibit, American Printed & Published Books Before 1850 on Agriculture, Horticulture & Botany, 1936 January-February; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Book Exhibit, 1934 February 14-March 24; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Library Committee, Bartoniana, New York City, 1937 January; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Library Committee, Books and Autographed Letters from the Collection of Mrs. Roy A. Hunt, 1943 February; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Library Committee, Chinese Exhibition, 1940; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Library Committee, Chinese Gardens and Their Influence, undated; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Library Committee, Ernest H. Wilson Exhibition, 1941; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - Garden Club of America, 1926 March-1945 November; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 10)
        bulletins
      - Garden Club of America, 1947 July; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 1)
        Gold Bulkley Medal, Bulletin of the Garden Club of America, pp. 2 and 54
      - Garden Club of America, 1922; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 2)